Guide to the Joan Ormondroyd papers, 1976-1990.
Ormondroyd, Joan papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Joan Ormondroyd papers, 1976-1990.
13-10-3147
Joan. Ormondroyd
1.8 cubic feet.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, speeches, publications, videocassesttes, and information on various conferences and workshops related to Ormondroyd's work as head of reference and instruction at Uris Library, Cornell University; including her work on bibliographic instruction.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Librarian, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, speeches, publications, videocassesttes, and information on various conferences and workshops related to Ormondroyd's work as head of reference and instruction at Uris Library, Cornell University; including her work on bibliographic instruction.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ormondroyd, Joan.; Cornell University -- Libraries.; Cornell University Library.; Cornell University; Cornell University. Library
Subjects:
Librarians -- New York (State).; Library orientation.; Librarians; Libraries; Library orientation
Places:
New York (State)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Print Materials
Series II. Media
CONTAINER LIST
- Print Materials
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Cornell library handbooks, 1950-1976 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Speeches and publications, 1951-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Guides and collection booklets, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Speeches and publications, 1970-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Personnel, 1971-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Handouts Olin past, 1972-1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Speeches and publications, 1973-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Speeches and publications, 1974-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - General, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - General, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conferences and workshops attended, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Statistics instruction, 1976-1999 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Handouts and signs, Cornell, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Slide tape, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Instruction archive handouts, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Government publications, instruction handouts, 1980-1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Handouts, CUL past, 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Speeches and publications, 1986-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Speeches and publications, 1986-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Instruction planning document, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Kodak Data show operator manual, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Conferences and workshops attended, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - HSS 315 Human sexuality, 1988-1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Online catalog instruction materials, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Research seminars handouts, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Theatre grads, 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Freshman writing seminar, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Course transparencies, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Cite and Byte, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Uris policies, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Gov. 131, 1992-09-1992-11 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Govt. 111, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Instruction Ctr proposal, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Instruction statistics, 1994-1998 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Handouts, Olin/Uris reference study group final report, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Africana studies 100.1 Black male writers, 1998-2009 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - AS and RL 100.2, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Instruction lab policies, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Box of index cards, instruction bibliography, annotation cards, Date Unknown (Box 1)
  - U.S. Government Documents: an introductory slide presentation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Olin handouts, old masters, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Green cards, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Original floor plan, Uris Library, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Media
  - Magnetic tape, 1977; TR-171347 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Teaching Librarians to Teach, 1978-1979; V-10674 (Box 2)
  - Teaching Librarians to Teach #4 Eric Reukenkamp, 1978-1979; V-10675 (Box 2)
  - Excerpts from Teaching Librarians to Teach, 1978-1979; V-10676 (Box 2)
  - Undergraduate Research, 1981; V-10678 (Box 2)
  - Search Strategy with Joan Ormondroyd, 1981; V-10673, 10679 (Box 2)
  - Library meeting part 2, 1989-01-17; V-10672 (Box 2)
  - The Art and Science of Teaching, Undated; V-10677 (Box 2)
  - Teaching program in Master of Arts, Undated; V-10680 (Box 2)
  - Government Documents (short vers), Undated; TR-17113 (Box 2)
  - Government Documents (long vers), Undated; TR-17114 (Box 2)